Zhengzhou Huang

Phone: +1 858-214-4697 | **Email**: zhua05nuo@outlook.com

Portfolio: https://zhengzhou-huang.me/Records/project-highlights.pdf **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/zhengzhou-huang-nuobe/

Zhengzhou is a multimedia artist and designer working in 2D/3D graphics, videos, animations as well as interactive media such as websites, UI/UX(web+mobile) and games. He is an Independent and collaborative maker who actively takes part in projects from concept to implementation. Having experience in commercial, educational, and art fields, Zhengzhou is versatile and innovative with a variety of styles, workflows and software applications.

Education

University of California Los Angeles (UCLA), Los Angeles, CA

06/2021

MFA, Design Media Arts

University of California San Diego (UCSD), La Jolla, CA

06/2019

BA, Visual Arts Studio

- Magna Cum Laude
- Phi Beta Kappa

Skill

- 2D/3D Graphics, Web, and UI/UX Design: Blender 3D, Autodesk Maya, RealityCapture, Photoshop, Illustrator, XD, InDesign, Figma, Wordpress, Squarespace, RunwayML
- Videography and Animation:
 After Effects, Premiere Pro, Audition, Blender 3D
 Maya, VR video
- Web Front-End and Interactive Development:
 HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, CPanel, Responsive Design/Development, SVG animation, LottieFiles, Webpack, Unity, C#, Github, Processing, Arduino
- Soft Skills: Concept building, Problem-Solving, Detail-Oriented, Time Management, Communication, Collaboration

Work Experience

Kindred Spirit, Remote

02/2022 - present

Freelancer (Web Design and Development)

- Brainstorm and redesign page layouts and UX for the company website. Update and add UI features.
- Make web wireframe and prototype; mockup image/text layouts, graphics and motion in Adobe XD.
- Customize layout, interaction and responsive designs with HTML and CSS in Squarespace.

Advanced Continuing Education Association (ACEA), Remote

08/2021 - 12/2021

Web and Graphics Designer, Internship

- Conceptualized design of landing page; analyzed its user group properties and brand image.
- Designed the UI/UX for the company's landing page, including layout, responsive fonts/interface, graphics, animation, procedural motion, prototypes and user flow.
- Front-end development of the landing page with HTML, CSS and JavaScript including responsive design, SVG animation, scroll interactivity, optimization and browser compatibility.
- Created marketing mini-demo animations for the company product using Adobe After Effects and Lottie
 Animation
- Designed vector illustrations and graphics for the company web application using Adobe Illustrator and Figma.
- Communicated and collaborated with colleagues through Slack, Google Suite tools and gave constructive feedback to each other.

Department of Design Media Arts, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA

06/2021 - 08/2021

Lecturer

• Taught DESMA 24: Motion, https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Summer21/24, about theory and practice of 3D modeling and animation, video production, as well as Al generated images.

- Led study and practice in 3D and 2D motion software such as Autodesk Maya, Adobe After Effects, Premiere Pro and Runway ML.
- Led lectures, discussions and screenings to study critical concepts and tools to make creative time-based media works.

Department of Design Media Arts, UCLA, Los Angeles, CA

09/2019 - 06/2021

Teaching Assistant

- Designed and developed websites to manage course contents and students' art and design projects using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and jQuery as well as CMS platforms like Wordpress. Lead and participated in stages of brainstorming, UI/UX prototype to execution.
- Led meetings and discussions for essential course materials and extra information on art and design practice.
- Supported students in the concepts and techniques of their projects including videos, websites, animations.
- Coordinated with visiting professionals to give in-class talks.
- A list of courses:
 - o 03/2021 06/2021: Senior Projects: Interactivity and Games
 - o 01/2021 03/2021: Video
 - o 09/2020 12/2020: Special Topics in Video and Animation, https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Fall20/172
 - o 09/2020 12/2020: Media Arts: Introduction
 - o 01/2020 03/2020: Media Histories, https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Winter20/8
 - o 09/2019 12/2019, Design Culture

Exhibitions / Shows

2021 -

- <u>Society for Literature, Science and the Arts (SLSA) Poster Exhibition</u>, Penny W. Stamps School of Art & Design at the University of Michigan, 09/2021
- The Last Online Show, Design Media Arts MFA thesis show, University of California Los Angeles, 05/2021
- <u>Air</u>, solo show of a collaboration work at Department of Design Media Arts, University of California Los Angeles, 02/2021

2020 -

- Share Screen, Design Media Arts fall preview show, University of California Los Angeles, 10/2020
- <u>D02.2</u>, Plicnik Space Initiative, Online Exhibition, 10/2020

2019 -

- Here/After, Senior Art Exhibition, University Art Gallery, University of California San Diego, 06/2019
- Honors Thesis Show, Adam D. Kamil Gallery, University of California San Diego, 06/2019
- Honors Open Studio, Upper Mandeville, University of California San Diego, 03/2019

2018 -

- Children's games public showcase and demo night, Structural and Material Engineering Building, University of California San Diego, 09/2018
- Other Art: Art + Music Festival, organized by Mi Mate, Sun God Lawn, University of California San Diego, 05/2018

Award

Clifton Webb Scholarship, University of California Los Angeles, 2020 - 2021

Dr. Hyman Eugene Oxman & Frieda Dreyer Oxman Fellowship, University of California Los Angeles, 2020 - 2021 Russell Foundation Grant, University of California San Diego, 2018

Visual Arts Department Class Grant for Studio Art, University of California San Diego, 2017

Magna Cum Laude, University of California San Diego, 2019

Initiated as a member of Phi Beta Kappa Sigma Chapter, University of California San Diego, 2019

Marshall College Honors, University of California San Diego, 2015-2019

Publication

Fall 016 Issue: Chaos // Disorder , Acropolis Art Magazine, College of William and Mary, 2016